<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cars on Dripping Data</title>
    <link>/tags/cars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cars on Dripping Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/cars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Electric Vehicle Parking at Honolulu International Airport</title>
      <link>/2016/12/29/electric-vehicle-parking-at-hnl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/29/electric-vehicle-parking-at-hnl/</guid>
      <description>In Hawaii, electric cars park for free at state owned parking lots. This is a big benefit when we travel since the airport parking lot is normally $18 per day. I wondered how much money the state loses on the electric car parking at the airport. Because I travel to Maui every week for work, I was able to collect some data to try to answer this question.
Methods I made video recordings of parked cars while driving through the Honolulu International Airport interisland parking structure between November 29, 2016 and December 28, 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gas vs. Electric Car Operating Prices in Honolulu</title>
      <link>/2016/09/11/electric-car-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/11/electric-car-economy/</guid>
      <description>Our family has an electric car (Nissan Leaf) and a hybrid (Toyota Prius), and we often have to choose which one we will take out on the weekend. I wondered which one was cheaper to operate and which one was better for the environment.
Wallet Impact The Leaf travels about 4.8 miles per kilowatt hour (kwh), and the Prius gets about 55 miles per gallon (mpg). Our electricity costs about $0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>