<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parking on Dripping Data</title>
    <link>/tags/parking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parking on Dripping Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/parking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Electric Vehicle Parking at Honolulu International Airport</title>
      <link>/2016/12/29/electric-vehicle-parking-at-hnl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/29/electric-vehicle-parking-at-hnl/</guid>
      <description>In Hawaii, electric cars park for free at state owned parking lots. This is a big benefit when we travel since the airport parking lot is normally $18 per day. I wondered how much money the state loses on the electric car parking at the airport. Because I travel to Maui every week for work, I was able to collect some data to try to answer this question.
Methods I made video recordings of parked cars while driving through the Honolulu International Airport interisland parking structure between November 29, 2016 and December 28, 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse-In Parking in Hawaii and California</title>
      <link>/2016/07/14/reverse-parking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/14/reverse-parking/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One of my mainland-born friends is annoyed that Hawaii drivers like to reverse their cars into parking stalls much more than the mainland. My wife, who is also from the mainland, agreed with him enthusiastically. Whether this is appropriate parking behavior or not, I had never noticed it before, so I figured it was something I could test with some observations. I had a trip coming up to the mainland, and I was able to collect some data to test whether the Hawaii drivers were really so different than their California counterparts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>