<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports on Dripping Data</title>
    <link>/tags/sports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports on Dripping Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitchers with More Saves than Strikeouts</title>
      <link>/2017/05/21/saves-vs-strikeouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/21/saves-vs-strikeouts/</guid>
      <description>On my favorite fantasy baseball podcast, the host mentioned the phenomenon of pitchers who had more saves than strikeouts. This seemed like it would be fairly uncommon since it seems that many closers are power pitchers (e.g., Aroldis Chapman). I decided to investigate further using the Lahman database.
Methods I used the Lahman database again, which is perfect for answering this kind of questions. It has a Pitching table that contains season long stats for every pitcher from 1871 to 2015 (as of this post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Runs and Other Factors on Team Saves in Major League Baseball</title>
      <link>/2017/04/18/saves-and-runs-scored/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/18/saves-and-runs-scored/</guid>
      <description>From listening to my favorite fantasy baseball podcast it seems that there is a belief that teams that score lots of runs are not likely to produce saves. The idea seems to be that such teams would blow out their competitors and so have less opportunity for games to be saved. While it made sense, I wondered what the data said.
library(dplyr) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;: ## ## filter, lag ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, union library(ggplot2) library(Lahman) data(&amp;quot;Teams&amp;quot;) Teams &amp;lt;- tbl_df(Teams) Exploration of Saves over Time Saves did not become an official statistic until 1969 (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baseball Team Season Save Leaders with the Lowest Totals since 2000</title>
      <link>/2017/03/31/baseball-team-season-saves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/31/baseball-team-season-saves/</guid>
      <description>I was listening to my fantasy baseball podcast last week, and the conversation turned to the Phillies closer situation. One host suggested that the Phillies might not have any pitcher with more than 10 saves this season. The other host thought that this would be unlikely. They looked quickly at the data and found that this has happened a few times since 2000. I wondered if there was a way to look this up using the Lahman database in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Unlucky Fantasy Football Season Is Over</title>
      <link>/2016/11/30/unlucky-fantasy-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/30/unlucky-fantasy-football/</guid>
      <description>The regular fantasy football season just finished, and as usual, my team underperformed. I had the 3rd most points in the league and finished 7 out of 8 teams with a record of 4-8. I wondered what were the chances of such a bad record. This called for a simulation!
Methods I transcribed all the scores for each game into a spreadsheet and loaded it into R.
library(dplyr) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;: ## ## filter, lag ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, union dat &amp;lt;- read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Yards of Offense by a College Football Team in a Shutout Loss</title>
      <link>/2016/10/03/football-shutouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/03/football-shutouts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The purpose of this document is to explore the most yards in a shutout loss for a college football team. It was inspired after the University of Hawai`i gave up 462 yards in shutting out San Jose State on November 15, 2014. I wanted to see if I could use the dplyr package to explore this question.
library(dplyr) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;: ## ## filter, lag ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, union  Data Source To obtain a source of data, I downloaded a database of football game statistics from 2000-2013, from http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>